A Guide to the Rose Greely Architectural Drawings & Papers, 1909-1985
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Rose Greely Architectural Drawings and Papers 1909-1985
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10772
This collection consists of 1,467 items (3 Hollinger boxes and 14 Oversize folders, ca. five linear feet).
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The Rose Greely Collection was transferred to the Library from the Fiske Kimball Fine Arts Library, University of Virginia, by Jack Robertson, on July 14, 1988.
Biographical/Historical Information
Greely was born in Washington, D.C., to the Army officer and Arctic explorer, General Adolphus W. Greely, and Henrietta H.C. Nesmith Greely. She studied a variety of art forms at several institutions, such as the Maryland Agricultural College; the Art Institute of Chicago (interior decorating); metal work in Washington, D.C.; and a year's study of silver repousse work and enamelling on metal in Florence, Italy, before she decided to combine her enthusiasm for design and horticulture in a degree in landscape architecture. She attended the Smith College Graduate School of Architecture and Landscape Architecture for Women in Cambridge, Massachusetts (then known as the Cambridge School of Domestic and Landscape Architecture) under the direction of Henry A. Frost, a professor in the Harvard Architecture School and graduated in [1920?].
Upon graduation, Greely worked for Fletcher Steele, a landscape architect in Boston, and was on the staff of the magazine House Beautiful for a year before returning to Washington, D.C.. There she worked as a draftsman for Horace W. Peaslee, concentrating on landscaping problems.
Greely entered into her own practice in 1925 and worked on many different types of projects, including many Washington homes, the grounds of Army Posts, schools, real estate developments, government housing projects, outdoor theaters, playgrounds, roads, gardens, country estates, New England farms, and a garden in Mexico. Most of the drawings in this collection are of private residences and estates, which are listed by the name of the owner or institution. Greely was also the only woman to work on the Advisory Committee of the Williamsburg, Virginia, Restoration Project. Much of the above information was derived from an article "Rose Greely, L.A." in Home Acres Edition Garden Digest(1941 January).
Scope and Content Information
This collection consists of 1,467 items (3 Hollinger boxes and 14 Oversize folders, ca. five linear feet), 1909-1985, and contains the architectural drawings (657 drawings) and papers of the landscape architect Rose Greely, Washington, D.C.. Rose Greely was one of the earliest graduates from the Cambridge School of Domestic and Landscape Architecture in [1920 ?]. She was licensed as an architect in the District of Columbia in 1926 and elected a Fellow of the American Society of Landscape Architects in 1936. Much of her work in landscape architecture was accomplished in Washington, D.C., and surrounding areas.
Organization
The first series of this collection consists of the architectural drawings by Rose Greely for various residences, estates, and gardens. For a detailed description of each separate sheet see the inventory in Box 2. Each drawing with a Greely number noted in the folder listing can be located in the inventory under that number. The drawings are also listed alphabetically by the name of the owner or institution in the appendix at the end of the guide. The appendix to the guide lists owner, the drawing's Greely inventory number, and all of the folder numbers containing drawings rendered for that owner. Since the drawings for the same residence may be in different sizes, they may be in as many as three separate folders. Please consult the appendix on pages 16-19 of this guide for a list of all folders containing each individual clients drawings.
The second series contains client files kept by Rose Greely which are chiefly concerned with residences in Washington, D.C., Maryland, Virginia, Vermont, New Mexico, and Georgia. Other files include those for the Garden Club of America, the National Rock Garden in Rock Creek Park, The Madeira School, Greenway, Virginia, Place de la Liberte, Brussels, Belgium, the Potomac Rose Garden, and the Williamsburg, Virginia, Restoration Project. Not all clients whose drawings are present in the collection are represented by a file.
Miscellaneous papers comprise the third series and include: articles and talks by Rose Greely; some biographical information concerning Greely; a client list, notes, and inventory of Rose Greely drawings compiled by the Fiske Kimball Fine Arts Library; the correspondence of Rose Greely; correspondence of the Fiske Kimball Fine Arts Library concerning the Rose Greely Collection; printed matter concerning garden tours; examples of gates, walls, drives, etc.; photographs of the Greely cabin in New Hampshire, Italian Architecture, the Rebsamen estate, Little Rock, Arkansas, and Tudor Place, Washington, D.C.; a thesis by Rose Greely entitled, "Report on a Proposed Cooperative Farm Community" (1920); and a sketchbook belonging to Greely.
Contents List
- I: Architectural Drawings
  - Bernstein, Mr. & Mrs. Leo M., Tracy Place, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 9), 4 sheets 1952 (Folder 1)
  - Buchanan, The Honorable & Mrs. Wiley, 4220 Nebraska Avenue, N.W. Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 49), 9 sheets 1955 (Folder 1)
  - Cafritz, Morris, 2301 Foxhall Road (Gr. # 50), 14 sheets 1937-1938 (Folder 1)
  - Connor, General & Mrs. William D., 2412 Tracy Place, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 8), 2 sheets 1948 (Folder 1)
  - Covington, Mrs. J. Harry, 2320 Wyoming Avenue, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 33), 5 sheets 1936, 1940, 1947-9 (Folder 1)
  - Ford, Mrs. Sherman, 29 Kalorama Circle, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 17), 2 sheets 1944 (Folder 1)
  - Gore, Miss Mary, River Road, Potomac, Maryland, Swimming Pool Area (Gr. # 60), 5 sheets 1950-1951 (Folder 1)
  - Hauge, Mrs. Gabriel, 3500 Lowell Street, Washington, D.C., 2 sheets 1953 (Folder 1)
  - McLean, Mrs., Pool, (Gr. # 68), 2 sheets 1925 (Folder 1)
  - St. Timothy's School, Miss Watkin's Garden, Stevenson, Maryland, (Gr. # 48), 19 sheets 1952-1958 (Folder 1)
  - Williams, Mr. & Mrs. R.W., Baltimore, Maryland, (Gr. # 47), 3 sheets 1946, 1948 (Folder 1)
  - Bolton, Mrs. Chester C., 2301 Wyoming Avenue, Washington, D.C., Study "A", (Gr. # 55) 1947 (Folder 2)
  - Burden, Mr. William A.M., 1224 30th Street, Washington, D.C., Swimming Pool (Gr. # 45), 5 sheets n.d. (Folder 2)
  - "A Child's Playhouse and Garden" n.d. (Folder 2)
  - Coffey, Dr. & Mrs. Robert J., 4936 Loughboro Road, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 72) 1954 (Folder 2)
  - Decker, Mr. & Mrs. Samuel J., 2700 Chesapeake Street, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 5), 5 sheets 1954 (Folder 2)
  - Eddy, Miss Ruth, Old Bennington, Vermont, (Gr. # 14), 3 sheets 1954 (Folder 2)
  - Folger, Mr. & Mrs. J.C., 2991 Woodland Drive, Washington, D.C., (Gr. # 52), 21 sheets 1942-3, 1951-1955 (Folder 2)
  - Iron & Grillwork Examples, (Barker, Lansing, Wanamaker) 3 sheets 1926, n.d. (Folder 2)
  - Murray, Mr. & Mrs. Lewis N., Dunkirk, New York, Gardner's House, (Gr. # 54), 5 sheets n.d. (Folder 2)
  - Purdy, James H., 2818 31st Street, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 10), 2 sheets n.d. (Folder 2)
  - Riggs, Admiral & Mrs. Ralph, Rockville, Maryland 1953 (Folder 2)
  - Stead, Mrs. Dorothy, 3216 "O" Street, Washington, D.C., (Gr. # 13), 2 sheets 1955 (Folder 2)
  - Simpson, Mr. & Mrs. Lester C., Marlan Forest, Alexandria, Virginia, 4 sheets 1951-1953 (Folder 3)
  - Taylor, Mr. & Mrs. William H., Residence, 28 th and "Q" Streets, Washington, D.C., 63 sheets 1936-1937 (Folder 3)
  - Bernstein, Mr. & Mrs. Leo M., Tracy Place, Washington, D.C., Terrace & Azalea Garden, (Gr. # 9) 1952-1953 (Folder 4)
  - Bradley, Mr. & Mrs. Fontaine, 1820 45 th Street, Washington, D.C., Garden Terrace and Pool, (Gr. # 66) 1958 (Folder 4)
  - Buchanan, The Honorable & Mrs. Wiley, 4220 Nebraska Avenue, Washington, D.C., (Gr. # 49), 11 sheets 1955 (Folder 4)
  - Cosmos Club, Washington, D.C., Ground Floor Plan, (Gr. # 7), 4 sheets 1941 (Folder 4)
  - Duer, Mr. & Mrs. Beverley, Leesburg, Virginia, (Gr. # 18), 3 sheets 1947-1949 (Folder 4)
  - Eustis, Mrs. Hendrick, Warrenton, Virginia, Swimming Pool Area, (Gr. # 39), 2 sheets 1946 (Folder 4)
  - Hahm, Emma T., 6036 Daniels Road, Washington, D.C., (Gr. # 22), 5 sheets 1926-7, 1938 (Folder 4)
  - McCormick, Mrs. Medill, Washington, D.C., Bowling Green & Playhouse Area, (Gr. # 42), 4 sheets 1929-1931 (Folder 4)
  - Rebsamen, Raymond, Topographic Map of the Property, 2500 North Jackson Street, Little Rock, Arkansas, (Gr. # 19), 2 sheets 1949 (Folder 4)
  - Schley, General & Mrs. Julian, 2815 Dumbarton Street, Washington, D.C., Rails from Potomac Iron Works, (Gr. # 29), 2 sheets 1953 (Folder 4)
  - Tyssowski, Col. & Mrs. John, Cobbler Mountain Farms, Delaplane, Virginia, General Design & Topographic Surveys, (Gr. # 51), 3 sheets 1947 (Folder 4)
  - Walker, Mrs. Albert, Sea Island, Georgia, Planting Plan, (Gr. # 15), 13 sheets 1950-1952 (Folder 4)
  - Bogan, Mr. & Mrs. Eugene, 3115 Cleveland Avenue, Washington, D.C., General Design Plan, (Gr. # 36), 8 sheets 1953-1955 (Folder 5)
  - Commanding Officers Quarters- Aberdeen Proving Grounds, Maryland, Study of Planting, (Gr. # 44), 3 sheets 1934 (Folder 5)
  - Gawne, Mrs. J.O., 2439 Tracy Place, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 73) 1943 (Folder 5)
  - Harkness, Mr. & Mrs. Richard, 3035 Dumbarton Avenue, Washington, D.C., Pergola, (Gr. # 69), 2 sheets 1947 (Folder 5)
  - Hearst, Mr. & Mrs. William R., Jr., 2202 Decatur Place, Washington, D.C., Plan for the Gardens, (Gr. # 64) 1948 (Folder 5)
  - Lanahan, Mr. & Mrs. Samuel, 1224 30th Street, Washington, D.C., Garden Pool, (Gr. # 58), 4 sheets 1955 (Folder 5)
  - Le Clair, Col. & Mrs. H.P., Friendship, Maryland, General Design Plan for the Grounds (Gr. # 61) 1938 (Folder 5)
  - Lodge, Senator & Mrs., 3132 "O" Street, Washington, D.C., Construction Plan (Gr. # 63) 1948 (Folder 5)
  - Morris, Mr. & Mrs. George M. Morris, Kalorama Road, Washington, D.C., General Design Plan, (Gr. # 71) 1935 (Folder 5)
  - Place de la Liberte, Brussels, Belgium, Memorial to King Albert, 6 sheets 1938 (Folder 5)
  - Shomo, Mr. & Mrs. Leslie C., Alexandria, Virginia, General Design, (Gr. # 40), 3 sheets 1952, 1955 (Folder 5)
  - Shomo, Mr. & Mrs. Lester, 631 Oakland Terrace, Alexandria, Virginia, Planting & Construction Plan (Gr. # 40), 7 sheets 1955 (Folder 5)
  - Vandergrift, General & Mrs. A.A., Commandant's House, Marine Barracks, Washington, D.C., Design & Planting Plan, (Gr. # 46), 6 sheets 1944 (Folder 5)
  - Walker, Mrs. Albert W., Westmoreland Hills, Maryland, General Design Plan, (Gr. # 41), 3 sheets 1951 (Folder 5)
  - Wheeler, Mr. & Mrs. George, 2510 Foxhall Road, Washington, D.C., Construction Plan, (Gr. # 43), 5 sheets 1951 (Folder 5)
  - Bard, Mrs. Philip, Hurstleigh, 6 Meadow Road, Baltimore County, Maryland, Terrace & Rose Garden, (Gr. # 67), 9 sheets 1951-1954 (Folder 6)
  - Bruce, Mr. & Mrs. David, 1411 34 th Street, Washington, D.C., 9 sheets 1955 (Folder 6)
  - Garden Seat, # 2, 2 sheets n.d. (Folder 6)
  - Lawrence, Mr. & Mrs. John, "Hartwood," Sharpsburg, Pennsylvania, (Gr. # 24), 2 sheets 1939 (Folder 6)
  - Magnuson, Mrs. Paul, 3121 "O" Street, Washington, D.C., (Gr. # 26), 3 sheets 1948-1949 (Folder 6)
  - Paull, Mrs. Singleton, Wheeling, West Virginia, (Gr. # 23), 6 sheets 1952 (Folder 6)
  - Pawley, Mrs. William, "Belvoir," The Plains, Virginia, (Gr. # 1), 7 sheets 1951-1953 (Folder 6)
  - Strong, Mrs. L. Corrin, Washington, D.C. and Gibson Island, Maryland, (Gr. # 2), 11 sheets 1942-3, 1946, 1953-5 (Folder 6)
  - Bradford, Mr. & Mrs. William, Langley Farms, McLean, Fairfax County, Virginia, (Gr. # 32), 3 sheets 1946-1947 (Folder 7)
  - Kennedy, Gordon, 2915 Connecticut Avenue, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 16), 3 sheets 1946 (Folder 7)
  - Kienle, Mr. & Mrs. Eugene, Clay Point, Milton, Vermont, (Gr. # 25), 2 sheets 1947-1948 (Folder 7)
  - McLean, Admiral Ridley, Grounds of the Army, Navy, & Marine Corps Country Club Grounds, Arlington County, Virginia, (Gr. # 34), 2 sheets 1930 (Folder 7)
  - Masonic Memorial Garden, National Memorial Park, Falls Church, Virginia, (Gr. # 31) 1939 (Folder 7)
  - Parker, Mrs. Andrew, 4000 Nebraska Avenue, Washington, D.C., (Gr. # 30), 7 sheets 1954 (Folder 7)
  - Schwartz, Mr. & Mrs. Samuel T., 2860 Woodland Drive, Washington, D.C., (Gr. # 6), 30 sheets 1938-1955 (Folder 7)
  - Cushman, E.S., Shaftsbury, Vermont, Topography 1954 (Folder 8)
  - Evermay Service Court Gate Lantern, 2 sheets 1934 (Folder 8)
  - Gignoux, damaged torn sheet n.d. (Folder 8)
  - "Hillcrest" Wading Pool n.d. (Folder 8)
  - Horgan, Dr. Edmund, Topographical Map of the Estate, Delaplane, Virginia 1929 (Folder 8)
  - Van Emon, Mrs. C.G., Topographical Survey, Barnesville, Montgomery County, Maryland 1941 (Folder 8)
  - W.C. & A.N. Miller Developing Company Jobs # A-162, Loughboro Road, 11 sheets and # A-175, Van Ness Street, 7 sheets 1959 (Folder 8)
  - Washington Cathedral Garden, 2 sheets 1926-1927 (Folder 8)
  - Topographical Survey, Lot 159, 34 th and "O" Streets 1955 (Folder 8)
  - Burden, William A.M., 1224 30th Street, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 45) n.d. (Folder 9)
  - Eustis, Mrs. Hendrick, "Bellevue," Warrenton, Virginia (Gr. # 39), 10 sheets 1946-1947 (Folder 9)
  - Fletcher, Colonel & Mrs. Robert H., Leesburg, Virginia (Gr. # 37), 5 sheets 1937-1938 (Folder 9)
  - Hahm, Miss Emma T., 6036 Daniels Road, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 22), 2 sheets n.d. (Folder 9)
  - Hale, Mrs. Chandler (Gr. # 38), 3 sheets 1934-1935 (Folder 9)
  - Luttrell, Mrs. A. Lothrop, Bethesda, Montgomery County, Maryland, 2 sheets 1940 (Folder 9)
  - McCormick, Mrs. Medill, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 42), 8 sheets 1929-1931 (Folder 9)
  - Paull, Mary V., "Shawnee Hills," Wheeling, West Virginia (Gr. # 23), 4 sheets 1952 (Folder 9)
  - Rock Creek Park, Washington, D.C., 7 sheets 1932 (Folder 9)
  - Vandergrift, General & Mrs., Commandant's House, Marine Barracks, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 46) 1944 (Folder 9)
  - Walker, Mr. & Mrs. Albert Walker, Sea Island, Georgia, (Gr. # 15), 3 sheets, and Westmoreland Hills, Montgomery County, Maryland, (Gr. # 41), 2 sheets 1949-1951 (Folder 9)
  - Bruce, Mr. & Mrs. David Bruce, New Windsor, Carroll County, Maryland, 6 sheets 1956 (Folder 10)
  - Gore, Mary, "Marwood Estate," River Road, Montgomery County, Maryland, (Gr. # 60), 3 sheets 1950 (Folder 10)
  - Herron, General & Mrs. Charles Douglas, Cemetery Lot Bench and Marker 1948 (Folder 10)
  - Jeffries, L.E., "Muckross Estate," Fairfax County, Virginia 1929 (Folder 10)
  - Mallon, Mr. & Mrs. Paul, "Belle Haven," Virginia, 2 sheets 1939-1940 (Folder 10)
  - Murray, Mr. & Mrs. Lewis N., "Dunkeld," Dunkirk, New York (Gr. # 54) 1932 (Folder 10)
  - Parker, Andrew, 4000 Nebraska Avenue, Washington, D.C., Garden and Wall Panel, (Gr. # 30), 2 sheets 1943-1944 (Folder 10)
  - Potomac Rose Garden, West Potomac Park, Washington, D.C. 1945 (Folder 10)
  - Taylor, William H., 28th & Q Streets, Washington, D.C., 15 sheets 1937 (Folder 10)
  - Cosmos Club Garden Design, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 7), 2 sheets 1941 (Folder 11)
  - Covington, Mr. & Mrs. J. Harry, Wyoming Avenue, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 33), 1 sheet and "Minden Cottage," Craftsbury Common, Vermont (Gr. # 21), 4 sheets 1934-1937 (Folder 11)
  - Kienle, Mr. & Mrs. Eugene, Clay Point, Milton, Vermont (Gr. # 25), 3 sheets 1948 (Folder 11)
  - Lawrence, Mr. & Mrs. John W., "Hartwood," Sharpsburg, Pennsylvania (Gr. # 24), 4 sheets 1938-1939 (Folder 11)
  - Magnuson, Mrs. Paul, 3121 "O" Street, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 26) 1948 (Folder 11)
  - Montgomery, Mr. & Mrs. William, "Blythe Knoll," 6200 Nebraska Avenue, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 20), 5 sheets and (Gr. # 3) 3 sheets 1936-1950 (Folder 11)
  - Myers, Mr. & Mrs. George Hewitt, 2310 "S" Street, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 65) 1948 (Folder 11)
  - Pawley, Mrs. William, "Belvoir," The Plains, Virginia, (Gr. # 1), 3 sheets 1952-1953 (Folder 11)
  - Saul, Mr. & Mrs. Andrew, 3035 Chainbridge Road, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 4), 4 sheets 1941 (Folder 11)
  - Schwartz, Mr. & Mrs. Samuel T., 2860 Woodland Drive, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 6), 2 sheets 1938-1939, 1953 (Folder 11)
  - Strong, L. Corrin, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 2), 2 sheets n.d. (Folder 11)
  - Bernstein, Mr. & Mrs. Leo M., Tracy Place, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 9), 2 sheets 1952-1953 (Folder 12)
  - Brady, Mrs. James C., Jr., The Gardens at Mill House, Far Hills, New Jersey (Gr. # 35), 5 sheets 1933-1934 (Folder 12)
  - Connor, General & Mrs. William, 2412 Tracy Place, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 8), 2 sheets 1941 (Folder 12)
  - Duer, Mr. & Mrs. Beverley, "Woodburn," Leesburg, Virginia (Gr. # 18), 4 sheets 1946-1949 (Folder 12)
  - Duer, Miss Lucie, Warrenton, Virginia (Gr. # 12), 2 sheets 1948-1949 (Folder 12)
  - Erwin, Mrs. Henry D., "Arbremont" Perennial Garden (Gr. # 11) 1935 (Folder 12)
  - Ford, Mrs. Sherman, Twenty-nine, Kalorama Circle, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 17) 1944 (Folder 12)
  - Madeira School, Greenway, Virginia (Gr. # 27), 3 sheets 1933, 1936 (Folder 12)
  - Mason, Rosa Tucker, "Col Alto," Lexington, Virginia (Gr. # 28), 6 sheets 1937, 1940-1 (Folder 12)
  - National Memorial Park, Falls Church, Virginia (Gr. # 31), 6 sheets 1939 (Folder 12)
  - Purdy, Mr. & Mrs. James H., Jr., 2618 31st Street, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 10), 5 sheets 1947 (Folder 12)
  - Rebsamen, Mr. & Mrs. Raymond, 2500 North Jackson Street, Little Rock, Arkansas (Gr. # 19), 10 sheets 1949-1951 (Folder 12)
  - Schley, General & Mrs. Julian, 2815 Dumbarton Street, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 29), 2 sheets 1949 (Folder 12)
  - Barnes, Mr. & Mrs. James M., "Montevideo" (Gr. # 53), 3 sheets 1947-1950 (Folder 13)
  - Biddle, Mr. & Mrs. Francis, 1669 31st Street, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 62) 1947-1949 (Folder 13)
  - Bolton, Mrs. Chester C., 2301 Wyoming Avenue, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 55), 6 sheets 1947 (Folder 13)
  - Buchanan, Honorable & Mrs. Wiley T., 4220 Nebraska Avenue, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 49), 8 sheets 1955-1956 (Folder 13)
  - Cafritz, Mr. & Mrs. Morris, 2301 Foxhall Road, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 50), 15 sheets 1937-1938 (Folder 13)
  - Edmonston, Mrs. E.D., 2414 Tracy Place, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 56), 2 sheets 1947-1848 (Folder 13)
  - Folger, Mr. & Mrs. J.C., 2991 Woodland Avenue, Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 52), 12 sheets 1942-1951 (Folder 13)
  - Morley, Mr. & Mrs. Felix (Gr. # 70) 1934 (Folder 13)
  - St. Timothy's School, Stevenson, Maryland (Gr. # 48), 4 sheets 1952-1953 (Folder 13)
  - Tyssowski, Colonel & Mrs. John, "Cobbler Mountain Farms," Delaplane, Virginia (Gr. # 51) 1947 (Folder 13)
  - Simms, Mrs. Albert G., "Los Poblamos Ranch," Albuquerque, New Mexico (Gr. # 57), 43 sheets 1932-1934 (Folder 14)
  - Simms, Mrs. Albert G., Washington, D.C. (Gr. # 59), 3 sheets 1932 (Folder 14)
- II: Client Files
  - Bard, Mrs. Philip: Baltimore County, Maryland 1953-1956 (Box 1)
  - Bernstein, Leo M.: 2420 Tracy Place, Washington, D.C. 1951-1953, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Bolton, Mrs. Chester C.: 2301 Wyoming Avenue, Washington, D.C. 1947 (Box 1)
  - Bruce, Mr. & Mrs. David: 1411 34th Street, Washington, D.C. 1955-1956, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Bruce, Mr. & Mrs. David: Farm at New Windsor, Carroll County, Maryland 1955-1956 (Box 1)
  - Buchanan, Wiley: 4220 Nebraska Avenue, Washington, D.C. 1954-1956 (Box 1)
  - Eustis, Mrs. Hendrick: Warrenton, Virginia 1946-1947 (Box 1)
  - Folger, Mr. & Mrs. J.C.: 2991 Woodland Drive, Washington, D.C. n.d. (Box 1)
  - Garden Club of America: National Rock Garden in Rock Creek Park 1932 (Box 1)
  - Greely, Rose: Garden 1938-1965 (Box 1)
  - Kienle, Mr. & Mrs. Eugene: "Clay Point," Milton, Vermont 1948 (Box 1)
  - The Madeira School, Greenway, Virginia 1945 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous Clients 1945-1960 (Box 1)
  - Place de la Liberte, Brussels, Belgium 1944-1946 (Box 1)
  - Potomac Rose Garden 1952 (Box 1)
  - Schwartz, Samuel T.: 2860 Woodland Drive, Washington, D.C. 1948-1955 (Box 1)
  - Shomo, Lester: 631 Oakland Terrace, Alexandria, Virginia 1954-1955 (Box 1)
  - Simms, Mrs. Albert G.: Los Poblamos Ranch, Albuquerque, New Mexico (2 Boxs) 1932-1934, n.d. (Folder 1)
  - Simpson, Mr. & Mrs. Lester: Marlan Forest, Alexandria, Virginia 1951 (Box 1)
  - Strong, Mrs. L. Corrin: Washington, D.C./Gibson Island, Maryland 1943 (Box 1)
  - Taylor, William H.: Residence and Carriage House at Q and 28th Street n.d. (Box 1)
  - Walker, Albert W.: Sea Island, Georgia 1951-1952 (Box 1)
  - Williamsburg Committee of the American Society of Landscape Architects 1929-1930, 1941 (Box 1)
- III: Miscellaneous Papers
  - Articles featuring gardens designed by Rose Greely 1937-1954, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Articles by Rose Greely - Published 1922-1961 (Box 2)
  - Articles by Rose Greely - Unpublished 1933-1936, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Biographical & Professional Information re Rose Greely 1909-1946 (Box 2)
  - Client List of Rose Greely compiled by the Fiske Kimball Fine Arts Library n.d. (Box 2)
  - Correspondence of the Fiske Kimball Fine Arts Library re the Rose Greely Collection 1981-1985, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Correspondence of Rose Greely 1926-1954 (Box 2)
  - Fiske Kimball Fine Arts Library Notes re Rose Greely n.d. (Box 2)
  - Garden Tours (2 Boxes) 1929-1940, 1950, n.d. (Folder 2)
  - Gates, Walls, Drives, etc.: Notes and Other Material ca. 1936-1954 (Box 2)
  - Inventory of the Rose Greely Architectural Drawings made by the Fiske Kimball Fine Arts Library [ca. 1984 ?] (Box 2)
  - Photographs of the Greely Cabin in New Hampshire 1946-1948, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Photographs of Italian Architecture n.d. (Box 3)
  - Photographs - Miscellaneous [ca. 1949-1951 ?], n.d. (Box 3)
  - "Report on a Proposed Cooperative Farm Community" - Thesis in the School of Domestic Architecture and Landscape Architecture, Cambridge, Massachusetts 1920, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Sketchbook belonging to Rose Greely n.d. (Box 3)
  - Talks by Rose Greely 1934, 1945, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Travel Data 1932, 1956-1957 (Box 3)